Hello friends, I am Dr. Ved Prakash
Mishra your Anorectal Surgeon
welcome you to my YouTube channel.
We have started a process to find out
what methods we adopt in the treatment of piles.
In the same sequence, in the next
video we would like to tell
what is the role of rubber band ligation in the treatment of piles.
You must have heard that binding is done.
Perform rubber band ligation.  Let
us tell you about that.  Rubber band
ligation is basically a machine which has
rubber already mounted on it and we
hold the piles mass and put the rubber on it.
Due to this the pus
gradually dries up and the disease gets cured.
Rubber band ligation is
not very common today.  The reason for this is
that it is mostly used in first or second degree.
Most of the
patients who come to us are in advanced stage.
Those whose warts have grown bigger.
Therefore the entire wart cannot be held.  And
if a little bit of the outside is used,
above the dented line, then it becomes very painful.  That is why
we
use it very little today.  In patients where
surgical procedures cannot be performed,
we
use rubber band ligation in second degree.
Another complication of this is
infection.  If there is an infection,
an abscess forms there, causing great
discomfort to the patient.  Therefore its use is less.   The
advance version of this is
used today by gastroenterologists who do
binding.
Binding of piles items is done.  But rubber band
ligation is a temporary treatment which is
not successful for long and there is a
chance of recurrence.
For any information regarding this, contact on the number given below.
Thank you.